Amina Javed

113 Firth Park Crescent, Sheffield, S5 6HD | amjaved904@gmail.com | 07588319304

Personal Profile

I am a first-year Software Engineering student at Sheffield Hallam University. I am a hardworking individual who is dedicated and passionate about what I set out to do. In my pursuit of a career in the technological industry, I have developed efficient and effective problem-solving skills through my studies and work experiences to date.

Education

Degree | 2019-2023 | Sheffield Hallam University, Sheffield

BENG Software Engineering Year 1 modules include:

- Component Programming
- Fundamentals of Programming for Software Engineering
- Fundamentals of Computer Architecture
- Systems Modelling
- Mathematics for Software Engineering
- Professional Experience and Project Development.

A-Levels 2017-2019 Longley Park Sixth Form College, Sheffield

- Mathematics C
- Psychology C
- Biology B

GCSE | 2012-2017| Firth Park Academy, Sheffield

- 9 GCSEs A-B/6-7, including English, Maths and Science
- ECDL D*

Key Skills

- Adaptable I can quickly adapt to an environment such as during my NHS work
 experience I was required to quickly adapt to the fast-paced system that runs the catering
 department.
- Flexible during group work I can work around everyone's timetables and other commitments to allow us to work together as a group to complete the task that has been set

- **Punctual** during both my work experiences I was required to be punctual and be on time which I maintained throughout my time there.
- **Reliability** During my time in the NHS I had to be reliable as working within the hospital meant that patient's confidentiality could not be breached.

Technical Skills

I am currently learning programming languages such as C++, C# and HTML. I am proficient in the use of Microsoft Office. I have used online IDEs such as repl.it which is an online coding platform. Trello is another platform which I use to help me organise and prioritise my pieces of work.

Work Experience

Catering | Northern General Hospital, Sheffield | 27th June - 8th July 2016

As part of the Cutlers Ambassador Program, I was given work experience within the catering department. I was put within both dining rooms and the Central Processing Unit where all the food is made. My tasks were:

- Serving Food in the dining rooms as well as cleaning after the dining rooms had closed.
- Preparing and distributing the food needed for patients in the wards
- Cooking and packaging food in the CPU

Teaching Assistant | Hartley Brook Primary School Sheffield | 14th - 18th March 2016

Worked with children aged 3-5 within the nursery and classrooms. Tasks included:

- Helping children around the classroom with tasks such as reading and playing
- Lunchtime duty on the playground, monitoring the children
- Helping the classroom teacher with daily tasks such as getting the children ready for break and lunch.

Interests

I enjoy reading non-fiction books which helps benefit me with improving my literacy and a wider range of vocabulary. I also enjoy watching science-fiction films and am particularly fascinated by the technological advances used within the industry.

References

Available upon request